fidm.com 2017-11-04

# en | FIDM.edu

##### __Academic Honesty

All academic work submitted by a student must be original work.  Cheating or academic dishonesty includes, but is not limited to, all forms of giving or getting unauthorized help or using unauthorized materials on examinations and projects. This includes work that duplicates, in whole or part, that of another student when the assignment explicitly calls for individual expression.  Plagiarism, a form of cheating, involves obtaining or attempting to obtain academic credit by copying the words or ideas of another (from a book, magazine article, or website, for example) and passing them off as one's own without documentation – that is, without acknowledging the source with quotation marks, footnotes, and lists of works cited.  Cheating and plagiarism are cause for formal counseling.  Students who cheat or plagiarize will receive a "0" on the assignment and may be subject to further disciplinary action.  Violations of the academic honesty policy are reported to the Coordinator of Student Affairs (LA) or the Education Department (SF, OC, SD).

##### __Alcohol & Substance-Free Environment

FIDM is committed to providing a workplace and school environment free of alcohol, illegal drugs, un-prescribed drugs, or paraphernalia used for these substances.  Violation of this policy may result in immediate dismissal from academic programs or college-related employment. All FIDM campuses are smoke-free environments.  Smoking includes, but is not limited to, cigarettes, cigars, snuff, smoking tobacco, smokeless tobacco, nicotine, nicotine-delivering devices, chemicals or devices that produce the same flavor or physical effect of nicotine substances; and any other tobacco innovation.  Information on substance abuse programs, prevention awareness, and all other counseling services is available upon request and accessible on the FIDM Portal.

Download or view the Substance Abuse Prevention Program Brochure (PDF)

##### __Campus Conduct

FIDM is committed to a collegiate environment in which respect for others and proper conduct is demonstrated.  Hateful language – including profanity, racial, gender, or religious slurs – is unlawful and in direct opposition to an education environment.  FIDM promotes a professional environment free from hostility and will not tolerate harassing, bullying, intimidating, or threatening behavior or communication. Any violation will result in disciplinary action including suspension of services and/or privileges, or dismissal.

Students are responsible for conducting themselves as professionals while in the classroom and on the campus.  Eating and drinking are not permitted in FIDM’s classrooms, computer labs, halls, Library, or elevators.  Excessive talking, rudeness, or class disruptions will not be tolerated.  Electronic devices (mp3 players, cellular phones, etc.) are considered disruptive and must be turned off during class time and in any environment in which other students are studying, researching, or gathering for educational purposes, unless permitted by an instructor or designated staff member. In addition, FIDM respects the student’s right to express themselves through what they wear to campus, however we ask that they will exercise discretion in regard to their appearance choices to reflect a manner which suits a professional college student that does not cause undue attention or interfere with the educational process.

##### __Campus Safety & Access

FIDM is committed to the safety of its students, faculty, and staff.  Students are prohibited from bringing firearms onto any FIDM campus.  Students are prohibited from bringing firearms onto any FIDM campus. Illegal weapons or threatening gestures with an object that can be used as a weapon will lead to immediate dismissal.  Students are required to wear their valid FIDM Student Photo Identification cards where visible while on FIDM premises.  FIDM Student Photo ID cards may not be altered, copied, or forged and are non-transferable.  If a student is discovered loaning or altering a FIDM Student Photo ID card, that card will be confiscated and the student will face a mandatory appointment with the Coordinator of Student Affairs (LA), or Director of Education (SF, OC, SD).  Campus access is restricted to posted hours of operation. Please see FIDM Portal for hours of operation. Only registered students are permitted in the classroom. Authorized guests/visitors are not allowed on campus with prior approval and notification to Security from FIDM Staff for college business purposes (i.e., guest presenter, authorized vendor, campus meeting, etc.). All authorized visitors are required to check-in with the Security desk (LA)/Building Security (SF)/front desk (OC, SD) to obtain a guest/visitor pass. Students and faculty are not permitted to bring family, friends, or business acquaintances on campus.

##### __Copyright

**File sharing at FIDM**

File sharing of copyrighted works, such as commercial music and videos, is illegal. Students should review FIDM’s Student Technology Use Policy, which can be found in FIDM’s College Catalog. Additional information about student use of technology use may be found in FIDM’s Student Handbook & Planner, Faculty channel on the ePortal, and at the FIDM Portal at [http://myfidm.fidm.edu](http://myfidm.fidm.edu/).

##### Penalties for sharing copyrighted files

There are civil and criminal penalties for violation of federal copyright laws, which may be summarized as follows:

Copyright infringement is the act of exercising, without permission or legal authority, one or more of the exclusive rights granted to the copyright owner under section 106 of the Copyright Act (Title 17 of the United States Code). These rights include the right to reproduce or distribute a copyrighted work. In the file-sharing context, downloading or uploading substantial parts of a copyrighted work without authority constitutes an infringement.

Penalties for copyright infringement include civil and criminal penalties. In general, anyone found liable for civil copyright infringement may be ordered to pay either actual damages or "statutory" damages affixed at not less than $750 and not more than $30,000 per work infringed. For "willful" infringement, a court may award up to $150,000 per work infringed. A court can, at its discretion, also assess costs and attorneys' fees. For details, see Title 17, United States Code, Sections 504, 505.

Willful copyright infringement can also result in criminal penalties, including imprisonment of up to five years and fines of up to $250,000 per offense.

For more information, please see the website of the U.S. Copyright Office at <http://www.copyright.gov/help/faq/>.

##### Penalties for sharing copyrighted files

  * Do not use file sharing software, (also known as peer-to-peer or p2p software) to download copyrighted media. You MUST have the copyright owner's permission or your download is illegal!
  * Most programs that let you download songs and movies without payment share your computer's files to the Internet by default.
  * Popular file sharing programs used to distribute and obtain media illegally include: DropBox, BitTorrent, Gnutella, Warez P2P and many others. While these sites are not illegal, they are used for illegal activities.
  * Use legal downloading or subscription streaming services, such as Amazon, iTunes, YouTube, Netflix, to view media.
  * Do not share media you obtained legally, except as the copyright holder permits (iTunes streaming, etc.). Most file sharing software, by default, finds, advertises and shares all music and movies on your computer regardless of whether you have the right to share/upload these files.
  * Protect your computer from malicious software, by not installing file sharing software. While malware rarely installs file sharing software, that software is routinely exploited by criminals as provide a distribution channel for 'free' files that let them steal your information. Make sure you have obtained virus scanning and malware detection software above and beyond what Windows provides by default.

##### Laws Governing Illegal File sharing

##### __Defacing FIDM Property

Any student who defaces, vandalizes, or destroys FIDM property (including but not limited to library materials, computers, elevators, restrooms, parking structure, etc.) will be dismissed from the college.  All types of spray mount adhesive and spray paint are prohibited from being used on all FIDM campuses.

##### __Harassment & Sexual Misconduct Policy

FIDM is committed to providing a safe learning working environment for students and employees that is free of all forms of discrimination, harassment, exploitation, or intimidation. Sexual misconduct is a form of discrimination. All members of the college community should be aware that the college strongly opposes harassment and sexual misconduct and such behavior is prohibited by federal and state law and college policy. This policy applies to all FIDM community members, including students, faculty, administrators, staff, and third parties conducting business or having any official capacity with the college or on college property. FIDM is prepared to take prompt action to prevent and correct such behavior of individuals who engage in sexual harassment, as well as any other unlawful harassment based on factors such as race, ethnicity, religion, national origin, sexual orientation, gender identity, disability, or age. Violation of this harassment and sexual misconduct policy will not be tolerated and corrective action up to and including disqualification or termination may be taken. We encourage all students to report these incidents. FIDM is committed to protecting the privacy of all individuals involved in a report of sexual harassment, sexual misconduct, and sexual violence. Throughout the process of investigation of a report of harassment and sexual misconduct, every effort will be made to protect the privacy interests of all individuals, and respect and safeguard private information, to the extent possible consistent with the legal obligations of FIDM to investigate and respond effectively. Retaliation against a person who properly reports, complains about, or participates in the investigation of such harassment is strictly prohibited.

FIDM’s harassment and sexual misconduct policy and procedures are available in full on the FIDM Portal (under College Policies FAQs). Reports of sexual misconduct and inquiries concerning FIDM’s policy may be directed to the Title IX Coordinator at 213-624-1200 ext. 3025.

_**Affirmative Consent**_  
In alignment with California statute, FIDM’s policy concerning sexual assault, domestic violence, dating violence, and stalking, includes an affirmative consent standard in the determination of whether consent was given by both parties to sexual activity.  “Affirmative consent” means affirmative, conscious, and voluntary agreement to engage in sexual activity.   It is the responsibility of each person involved in the sexual activity to ensure that he or she has the affirmative consent of the other or others to engage in the sexual activity.  Lack of protest or resistance does not mean consent, nor does silence mean consent.  Affirmative consent must be ongoing throughout a sexual activity and can be revoked at any time.  The existence of a dating relationship between the persons involved, or the fact of past sexual relations between them, should never by itself be assumed to be an indicator of consent.

FIDM Sexual Misconduct Grievance Policy and Procedures (PDF)  
Reporting Options and Resources for Sexual Assault and Relationship Violence (PDF)  
Sexual Assault Risk Reduction Tips (PDF)

##### __Non-Discrimination Policy

FIDM in compliance with Civil Rights Legislation does not discriminate in its educational programs or employment practices on the basis of race, religion, national or ethnic origin, gender, sexual orientation, age, veteran status, disability, pregnancy, or any other characteristic or condition protected by federal or state law. These practices include, but are not limited to, hiring, employment promotion and transfer, admissions policies, the administration of its scholarship and loan programs and participation in the benefits and services of educational programs or related activities sponsored by the College. This policy is in accordance to Title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, Title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972, Section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973), Age Discrimination Act of 1975, California SB-195 Equity in Higher Education Act, and any other applicable federal, state and local law. Inquiries concerning FIDM’s policy may be directed to the Title IX Coordinator at 213-624-1200 ext. 3025.

##### __Policies & Services for Students with Disabilities

FIDM complies with the American with Disabilities Act of 1990 amended in 2008 (ADA), Section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act at 29 U. S. C. § 794 (Section 504), and any other federal, state and local law regarding students and applicants with disabilities.  It is college policy that no otherwise qualified individual with a disability, shall, solely by reason of disability, be excluded from the participation in, be denied the benefits of, or be subjected to discrimination under any program or activity of the college.

Each FIDM Campus has staff representatives designated to assist students with academic accommodations.  Students are required to provide verification of a disability and consult with the campus representative to develop a plan of reasonable accommodations upon matriculation to FIDM.

In order to receive reasonable accommodations, students diagnosed with learning, psychological, or physical impairment are required to meet with the campus representative to verify the disability.  Examples of documentation accepted by FIDM for a learning or psychological disability are an Individualized Education Plan (IEP), a 504 Plan, a psycho-educational evaluation or a psychological evaluation.  Accommodations cannot be provided unless verification is provided directly to the campus representative.  Students requesting accommodations receive the How to Request Accommodations form from the campus representative.  Once verification is established, the student and the campus representative discuss options for reasonable accommodations and complete the Student Academic Accommodations & Instructor Guidelines form.  The student then distributes the form to his/her instructor(s).  The documentation remains confidential for a period of seven years with the designated staff representative and is only released with the student’s signed consent.  Questions concerning FIDM’s policy, procedure, and accommodations should be forwarded to the campus representative.

##### __Solicitation/Distribution

The solicitation and distribution to students of non-FIDM materials and the use of the college facility for non-FIDM business purposes is prohibited.  Posting flyers, pamphlets, posters, or other means of advertising on the walls or bulletin boards and selling products on campus is not allowed.

#### Privacy Statement & Legal Notices

FIDM is committed to protecting your privacy. This FIDM Statement of Privacy applies to FIDM's family of websites and governs online data collection and usage at all FIDM sites and services. Please read the FIDM Statement of Privacy below and any supplementary information at the end of this statement for additional details about particular FIDM sites and services that you may use.

The FIDM family of websites are geared toward a general audience above the age of thirteen. FIDM does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of thirteen. This Statement contains a section which details FIDM's special policy regarding the collection and use of children's personal information. [Click here](http://www.ftc.gov/privacy/privacyinitiatives/childrens.html) to read more.

##### __Collection of your Personal Information

At some sites, FIDM collects personal information, such as your email address, name, home or work address, or telephone number. There is also statistical information about your computer hardware and software that is automatically collected by FIDM and may be shared with other websites within the FIDM family of websites. This information may include: your IP address, which is a number used by computers on the network to identify your computer so that data can be transmitted to you, your browser type, domain names, the time you accessed our website, and referring website addresses. This information is used by FIDM for the operation of the website service, to maintain quality of the website service, and to provide general statistics regarding the use of FIDM websites.

##### __Use of Cookies

FIDM's family of websites uses anonymous "cookies" for the purpose of analyzing web traffic on our sites. On occasion, cookies will also be used to help personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a web page server to help identify the user's computer and can be used to help FIDM recall your information on subsequent website visits. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. In order to use certain secure areas of the site, cookies must be enabled. If you have questions about how to enable "cookie" settings, please visit [http://www.enablecookies.org](http://www.enablecookies.org/).

##### __The Use of Your Personal Information

FIDM collects and uses your personal information to respond to or to deliver the information or services you have requested. For example, we gather your personally identifiable information when you send us email. We will use this information to respond to your email. FIDM may also use your personal information to inform you of other products or FIDM events.

We also use your information to help operate the FIDM family of websites. For example, to help us improve our website and to ensure that we make every effort to provide you with information and offers that are of interest to you, we may merge your personally identifiable information with click-stream data and other data we have (including offline data). We may also develop a non-identifiable profile on you based on the pages within our site that you visit.

##### __Sharing Your Information with Third Parties

We only share your personally identifiable information (such as your email address) with select third parties including our agents. These companies are prohibited from using that information for any purpose other than the limited stated purpose for which FIDM has hired them.

##### __Control of Your Personal information

You may choose not to provide us with any contact information; however, you will be unable to use certain features of our sites. You also may choose to unsubscribe from any of our services or on-line mailing lists at any time.

To unsubscribe from any of our services send an email to [webmaster@fidm.com](mailto:webmaster@fidm.com). In the body of the message, please include the following information:

  * Name of service or mailing list from which you wish to unsubscribe
  * Your name
  * Your email address

You may also access the personal information we have collected about you and correct any inaccuracies by sending an email to [webmaster@fidm.com](mailto:webmaster@fidm.com).

##### __Security of Your Personal information

FIDM strictly protects the security of the personal information you provide. FIDM secures your personal information on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment that is only accessible by a limited number of authorized persons. When highly confidential information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted over the Internet, it is protected with encryption, such as the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol.

##### __Collection and Use of Children's Personal Information

The FIDM family of websites is intended for users above the age of thirteen. FIDM does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from any child under the age of thirteen. When we do receive such information, we delete it as soon as we discover it and do not use it or share it with third parties.

##### __Third Party Links

This website contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy or merchant practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to read the privacy statements of each website that they visit. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected when you visit FIDM's family of websites.

##### __Changes to this Statement of Privacy

FIDM will occasionally update this Statement of Privacy to reflect student and customer feedback. When FIDM posts changes to this Statement, the date of the most recent update will appear at the top of the Privacy Statement page. If there are material changes to this Statement or in how FIDM will use your personal information, FIDM will prominently post such changes before implementing the change. FIDM encourages you to periodically review this statement to be informed of how FIDM is protecting your information.

##### __Contact Information

FIDM welcomes your comments regarding this Statement of Privacy. If you have any questions, please contact FIDM by email or postal mail.

You may contact us by email at [webmaster@fidm.com](mailto:webmaster@fidm.com).

You may contact us by postal mail at the following address:

The FIDM Publications Department – Statement of Privacy  
919 S. Grand Ave.  
Los Angeles, CA 90015 USA

##### __Copyright and Trademark Information

All contents of this internet site (including design; information; audio; video; photographs and graphic elements) are copyrighted by FIDM. Information herein may not be reproduced, transmitted, rebroadcast, published, re-written or distributed in any form without the expressed written consent of FIDM. This website may not may be "deconstructed" and its elements used without the expressed written consent of the copyright holder. Other company's trademarks used on this site are the sole property of individual owners and may not be used without their expressed written consent.

##### __SMS 57682 Shortcode Terms & Conditions

Message and data rates may apply. To stop receiving messages from our SMS shortcode service, reply STOP to any message. To receive more information regarding the SMS shortcode service, reply HELP to any message. The SMS Gateway provider is MessageMedia and provides FIDM with the ability to send SMS messages to the subscribed number for the purpose of delivering opted-in subscribers the information requested. If you have questions regarding the service, you may contact FIDM at 1.800.642.1200 or MessageMedia at 1.866.751.8337. Under normal circumstances we expect to send up to (2) messages per month. The FIDM mobile text service is designed to notify the subscriber of FIDM events, scholarships, careers, and programs for which a subscriber may be interested in. It is not binding, and without guarantee of event availability, and is subject to change without notice. It is also first come, first serve. So if you receive a message, take action. This service may not be available on all carriers. To determine if your carrier is supported, please contact MessageMedia support at 1.866.751.8337.

##### __Especially about FIDM

When you submit a Contact FIDM Form, FIDM requests personal information such as your name and email address. A FIDM representative will contact you to answer your question. You may also receive information to announce new features, technical issue updates, and news about FIDM products and events.

When you submit a FIDM Scholarship Competition Information Request Form, FIDM requests personal information such as your name, address, telephone number, and email address, as well as demographic information such as your birth date and high school graduation year. A FIDM representative will send you information about the scholarship competition. You may also receive information to announce new features, technical issue updates, and news about FIDM products and events.

When you apply to FIDM using the Online Application Form, FIDM requests personal information such as your name, address, telephone number, credit card, and email address, as well as demographic information such as high school graduation year, birth date, gender, ethnic code, primary language, degrees earned, U.S. citizenship, and name/location of high school. This information is necessary for FIDM to evaluate and process your application. A FIDM representative will contact you regarding your interest in applying to the school. You may also receive information to announce new features, technical issue updates, and news about FIDM products and events.

When you submit an Information Request Form, FIDM requests personal information such as your name, address, telephone number, and email address, as well as demographic information such as high school or college graduation year. A FIDM representative will contact you to answer your question. You may also receive information to announce new features, technical issue updates, and news about FIDM products and events.

##### __Especially about Fashion Club

When you sign up for Fashion Club, we request personal information, such as your name, home address, telephone number and email address, as well as demographic information such as your birth date and the year you plan to graduate from high school .

Fashion Club will use the information collected during registration for the following purposes:

  * Ensuring that users are over the age of thirteen
  * Performing service & support (e.g. responding to inquiries about becoming a FIDM student)
  * Sending information to announce new features, technical issue updates, and news about FIDM products and events

###### Contests

When your register for one of the contests hosted by Fashion Club, Fashion Club requests personal information such as your name, home telephone number, home address, and email address, as well as demographic information such as your birth date and gender. Fashion Club uses this information to notify you in the event that you are selected as a winner. Please see Fashion Club Contest Rules for more information. You may also receive information to announce new features, technical issue updates, and news about FIDM products and events.

###### Contact Us

For questions regarding the use of information collected on Fashion Club or for other concerns please contact:

Vicki Paganini  
Director of Marketing  
The Fashion Institute of Design & Merchandising  
919 S. Grand Ave.  
Los Angeles, CA 90015  
1.800.642.1200  
or 213.624.1200  
or contact by email at: vpaganini@fidm.com

##### __Especially about Ask the Librarian

When you submit an Ask the Librarian Form, FIDM requests personal information such as your name, city, state, telephone number, fax, and email address. A FIDM representative will contact you to answer your question. You may also receive information to announce new features, technical issue updates, and news about FIDM products and events.

##### __FIDM Student Portal

When you register for the FIDM Student Portal, FIDM requests that personal information such as your name, date of birth and email address be provided to register your account. You may also receive information to announce new features, technical issue updates, and news about FIDM products and events.

##### __Especially about Just for Educators

When you visit Just for Educators, we may collect personal information such as your name, phone number, school, and email addresses. FIDM may use this information to contact you regarding presentations, grant applications, and contests. Please see specific grant and contest rules for more information. You may also receive information to announce new features, technical issue updates, and news about FIDM products and events.

Every effort is made to ensure the accuracy of the information presented on Just for Educators. We sincerely regret any errors or omissions and request corrections be reported to [webmaster@fidm.edu](mailto:webmaster@fidm.edu). FIDM is not liable for damages caused by inaccuracies.

#### Bureau for Private Postsecondary Education
